（綱手）そろそろ着く頃か？
They should be getting there soon.
（シカク）ナルトですか？
（綱手）ああ。
Are you talking about Naruto?
Yes.
雷影は　ある場所としか
言わなかったが→
The Raikage wouldn't disclose
the exact location,
but he did say it was
the ideal place to lay low.
身を隠すには
もってこいの場所のようだ。
あとは　ナルトが　おとなしく
隠れていてくれるかどうかですね。
If only Naruto will do as
he's told and stay hidden.
戦争が始まると知ったら
あの性格からすれば→
Knowing his personality,
once he finds out
that war has broken out,
すぐに
戦場に出ようとするでしょう。
he'll want to rush out
onto the battlefield.
ナルトには　極秘のＳクラス任務に
派遣だと命じてある。
I told Naruto that he was going
on a highly classified
S-rank mission.
あとは　周りが
うまくフォローしてくれるだろう。
I'm sure the others will
follow along and play their parts.
（ナルト）タコ…　タコ　タコ！
（ヤマト）タコ？
Octopus, octopus, octopus!
Octopus?
An octopus is supposed
to help guide me.
導きのタコだってばよ。
Remember?
Giant Gramps Sage foretold it.
でかじいちゃん仙人が
予言した　あれ。
((ナルトよ　お前への予言を見た。
Listen, Naruto… I have seen
a prophecy involving you.
お前は　これから　タコに会う。
You will soon be meeting
an octopus.
Where is this octopus?
Can't you give more clues?
どこにいるタコなんだ？
もっと　ヒントねえの？
はっきりはせんが　ある孤島じゃ。
It's not clear,
but it's an isolated island.
People don't go near it.
人間は近づかん
生き物たちの楽園。
It's like a paradise for creatures.
わしからしたら
楽しそうなリゾートじゃ。
To me, it looks like
it would be a fun resort.
そこで　タコが
お前に協力してくれるはずじゃ。
And there, the octopus
should be of help to you.
(とにかく　導きがあるじゃろう))
In any case,
you will find your way.
そうか　タコだったね。
That's right, it was an octopus.
He was right about this being
an isolated island paradise.
楽園の孤島は
予言どおりだってばよ。
導きがあるってのも
きっと間違いねえ。
I'm sure there's no mistake about
meeting someone to guide me.
《ナルトのヤツ
まだ感づいていないようだな》
Naruto hasn't figured it out yet.
そろそろ
陸に上がる準備をしてください。
Please start preparing
to disembark soon.
おお！　島が見えてきたぞ！
Oh, I can see the island!
本当だ！！
No kidding!
ら…　楽園？
An…island paradise?
木ノ葉の
死の森みたいなもんです。
It's like the Hidden Leaf's
Forest of Death.
こっちのほうが
ちょっと過激ですが。
But this is a bit more extreme.
リゾート？
This is a resort?
Don't worry it's safe.
なに　安全ですよ。
As long as we don't provoke them,
the creatures are quite docile.
生物たちは　こちらから
何もしなければ→
おとなしいもんですから。
ただ　ひとつ…。
Except for one…
"Except for one" what?
ただ　ひとつ…　なんですか？
What part of this place
is a paradise?!
これの　どこが楽園じゃ！！
でかじいちゃん仙人のアホ！
You're a fool,
Giant Gramps Sage!
ここの海岸にすむ…。
For one that lives
along the shore…
あっ　タコの脚！
Huh? Octopus tentacles!
さあ　タコ！
俺を導いてくれってばよ！！
Okay, octopus!
Come and guide me!
ナルト　コイツは…。
Naruto, this is actually…
（ヤマト）イカだ！
a squid!
Land Ahoy!
Is this the Island of Paradise?
えっ…。
It's here!
で…　出た！　こ…　コイツだけには
気をつけないとって→
I was just about to warn you
that he's the one
you have to be careful about,
but he appeared before I could!
言おうとした矢先に…　出た！
（みんな）なに！？
– What?!
１…　２…　３…。
One, two, three…
脚　数えなくても
見りゃ　わかるでしょ。
It's obvious without
counting its tentacles!
Naruto, come on!
ナルト　やるよ！
あ…　でも　一応　確かめねえと。
But we should make sure.
A squid has ten legs.
An octopus has eight.
イカなら　１０本　タコなら　８本。
If this is the octopus who's going
to help guide me…
コイツが導きのタコだったりしたら
やっぱ　まずいことに…。
うわ～っ！！
ナルト！
Naruto?!
うげっ…。
あっ…。
（キラービー）イカは　すっこんでろ！
以下省略！
Squid go deviate…
The rest I abbreviate!
なんですか？　もう１匹
ダジャレ　しゃべりながら出てきたぞ。
What the—?!
Here comes another one
saying weird puns!
もう　ムチャクチャだ！
This is so confusing!
６…　７…　８…。
6, 7, 8…
It's an octopus!
タコだ！！
This one is an octopus!
今度こそ　タコだ！
タコなのか？
Is that really an octopus?
キラービー様！
Master Killer Bee!
Killer Bee?
キラービー？　じゃあ　このタコが。
Then this octopus is…
Y'all are late, ya fools, ya fools!
（キラービー）遅せえじゃねえか。
バカ野郎　コノ野郎。
It changed into a human?
人に変わった！
Hey, ya know Octopops, thanks!
タコのおっさん
ありがとうだってばよ！
Ya know…
だってばヨー？
RHYME NOTEBOOK
ん～　なに？
ん？
What?
KILLER BEE
THAT'S ME…YA KNOW!
コイツとは
合うか合わない　どっちかな。
Will we clash or be a smash?
If I dare say,
it'll be a no-go, whee!
いや　あえて言うなら
アウトだろ　ウィー！
I'm a brat-hatin' outlaw…
俺は　ガキが苦手なアウトロー！
何だ　この力入れてダジャレ言う
筋肉グラサン。
What's up with
this beefy guy in shades,
singing lame puns at
the top of his lungs?
《このおっさんが
導きのタコなのか？》
Is this geezer the octopus
who's going to guide me?
ダジャレではないです。
They're not puns.
It's his original style,
演歌のこぶしと
ラップのビートを合わせた→
a combination of Enka singing
to a rap beat. Enka Rap!
オリジナルスタイル　演歌ラップです。
演歌ラップ？
Enka rap?
（モトイ）お疲れだな　皆の衆。
Welcome, everyone!
I've been waiting for you.
待ってたぞ。
俺は　今回の世話役　モトイだ。
I am Supervisor Motoi
and I'll take care of your needs.
宿場に案内する。
I'll take you to your lodgings,
so please follow me.
ついてこい。
（ガイ）あ～　やっと着いたのか。
Oh, we're finally here?
（アオバ）さぁ　陸ですよ。
しっかりして　ガイさん。
We're standing on
solid ground, Guy.
Get a hold of yourself!
ああ。
ゲキマユ先生　大丈夫か？
Is Bushier Brow Sensei all right?
He never got over
his seasickness, did he?
結局
治りませんでしたね　船酔い。
We were at sea for a long time.
結構　長い航海でしたが。
あ～　長かった。
うっ　辛かった。
It sure was long.
It sure was painful.
Is this really a paradise?
楽園って　ホントここなのか？
あ～　まだフラフラする。
I still feel woozy.
うわ～っ！
Hey, King, no need to panic!
キングちゃん　慌てるな。
コイツらは　大丈夫だ。
These guys are okay.
It's a gorilla! A gorilla!
ゴリラだ　ゴリラ！
これは　ゴリラなのか？
Is this a gorilla?
ビーさんは
この島の猛獣たちの頂点にいて→
Master Bee stands at the top
of this island's hierarchy of beasts.
He's tamed them all.
すべて手なずけている。
だから　ビーさんがいる限り→
So as long as he is around,
it's safe here.
とても安全な場所でもある。
それに島のまわりには→
Furthermore, preeminent
Hidden Cloud shinobi
雲隠れの
優秀な忍が結界を張り→
maintain a barrier around
the island.
何か不審なものが近づけば→
We'll know immediately if
anyone suspicious approaches.
すぐにわかるようになっている。
《だから　ここが
監禁場所に選ばれたのか》
Which is why this place
was chosen to detain them.
いったい　あのグラサンおっさんって
何なんだ？
Who the heck is that
shades-wearing pops?
雲隠れの英雄のなかの英雄。
He is the Hidden Cloud's hero
among heroes.
英雄？
Hero?
He's someone who not only
tamed these wild animals,
猛獣だけじゃない。
he is a Jinchuriki
who can control Tailed Beasts.
尾獣すら
完璧にコントロールした人柱力。
お前と同じ人柱力だ。
八尾のな。
He is a Jinchuriki like you…
of Eight Tails.
八尾の人柱力？
The Eight Tails' Jinchuriki?
しかも　コントロールした？
あのおっさんが？
And he can control it?
That old guy?
キラービーさんだ。
He's Master Killer Bee.
ヨー！
Yo!
この島は　八尾をコントロールするために
修業した場所でもある。
This island is also
where he trained
to gain control over the Eight Tails.
えっ？
The Hidden Leaf can use this floor.
木ノ葉の衆は
このフロアを使ってくれ。
部屋数は十分にある。
There are ample rooms.
Eat all you want
食事は１階の大食堂で　ご自由に。
in the great dining hall
on the first floor.
Choose whatever rooms you want.
じゃ　部屋割りは　各自適当に。
では　明朝
７時のミーティングまで　解散。
We'll adjourn until the meeting
tomorrow morning at seven.
俺は　しばらく休むぞ。
I'm going to rest for awhile.
This island is also
where he trained
((モトイ：この島は
八尾をコントロールするために→
to gain control over
the Eight Tails.
(修業した場所でもある))
And there, the octopus should be
of help to you.
((とにかく
導きがあるじゃろう))
ってばヨーのガキか…。
Ahh, it's the "ya know" brat.
What's up?
何だ？
俺様のサインでも欲しいのか？
You want an autograph from me?
修業をつけてくれ。
修業？
Train me!
Train you?
俺ってば　九尾の人柱力だ。
I'm the Jinchuriki of the Nine Tails.
けど　まだ九尾を
コントロールできていねえ。
But I can't control it yet.
だから尾獣のコントロールの仕方を
教えてくれ。
So please teach me
how to control a Tailed Beast.
やなこった。
んっ！
No way.
俺様は　ブラザー雷影に
休暇命令を受けて　ここへ来た。
I came here because
my brother, the Raikage,
ordered me to take a vacation…
滅多にない休みを返上して→
Why should I give up
a rare vacation for that reason?
なんで　そんなこと
しなきゃならねえ。
バカヤロウ　このヤロウ。
Ya fool, ya fool!
おっさんも俺と同じ人柱力だろ！
Because we're both Jinchuriki!
Why won't you help me out?
だったら協力してくれても
いいじゃねえかよ！
態度がでかいな
居直りかいな　ウィー？
Your big attitude is suspect.
And now you're trying
to change the subject. Whee.
うっ…。
Old man, your shades are so hip.
おっさんのグラサン
顔も濃いけど　かっこいい　ウィー！
And your facial features are so thick,
but you're just so sick. Whee!
なかなかいいビート
刻むじゃねえか坊主。
Hey kid, you've got good style.
Yes! He's starting to like me!
《よっしゃ！
のってきたってばよ！》
ヨー！
ん？
Yo!
まずは挨拶だ。
First comes the greeting!
We start with fist bumps,
while we keep rapping.
俺様のグーにグーを重ねろ。
ビートかましながらな。
おっさんのグラサン　ウサンクサ！
Hey fuddy-duddy…
Those shades sure look funny, ah…
あっ…。
《しまった！
Shouldn't have said that!
えぇ～い　こうなったら！
Oh well, what the heck!
ハーレムの術！》
Harem Jutsu!
さんざんお願いしてるじゃない。
このおませさん。
I've been begging for
so long on my knees.
Come on, my dear.
コントロール教えて～ん！
Teach me control.
お願い。
Please…
《どうだってばよ。
How's that?
All men fall for this jutsu!
男は　この術に　みんな弱い》
あっ！
Hey old man! Old man!
おい　おっさん！　おっさん！
ケチ！
You're stingy!
《なんだよ　アイツ…
ダジャレばっかり言いやがって！
What's with that guy?!
All he does is talk in rhymes.
タコって　もっと別のタコに
決まってらぁ！》
Whoever heard of
an octopus that raps?!
What do you want?
何だ？
Show me how the old man
wearing shades
グラサンのおっさんが
八尾をコントロールした→
trained to control the Eight Tails.
修業っていうのを教えてくれ。
ここで修業したんだろ？
He trained here, right?
ああ　ビーさんのことか。
Oh, you're talking about Bee.
あのおっさん　俺のこと
相手にしてくんねえから→
He won't give me the time of day,
so I came to ask you instead!
アンタに聞きに来たんだってばよ。
俺に？
Me?
I don't care if he's the hero
of the Hidden Cloud or what…
雲隠れの英雄だかなんだか
知んねえけどよ→
He's stingy and stubborn,
and talks only in rhymes.
ケチで頑固で
ダジャレばっかり言いやがって！
同じ人柱力なら
俺のことだって→
We're both Jinchuriki,
so why can't he be
more understanding?
もう少しわかってくれても
いいだろうによ！
– I mean…
– What do you know about Bee?!
テメエにビーさんの何がわかる！？
If you keep complaining about him,
それ以上　グダグダ言ってたら
俺が許さねえぞ　ガキ！
I won't forgive you, kid!
テメエも人柱力なら　その存在が
どういう生き様を歩いてきたか→
If you're a Jinchuriki,
you can imagine the kind of life
he's had to lead, can't you?
だいたい想像できんだろ！
ああ　できるってばよ。
I sure can!
だったら　俺のことだって→
And that old man should be able
to imagine what it's like for me!
想像できるはずだろ
あのおっさん！
じゃあ　なんで俺が困ってんのに
助けてくんねえんだよ！？
So why won't he give me
a break when I need his help?
俺だって…。
Even I…
ビーさんは　お前のことを
ちゃんと見てる。
Bee has been watching
you all along.
何かわけがあって　そうしたんだ。
There's a reason for his actions.
えっ？
Did you introduce yourself to Bee?
お前　ビーさんと挨拶したか？
挨拶？
Introduce?
First comes the greeting.
((まずは挨拶だ。
俺様のグーにグーを重ねろ))
We start with fist bumps.
グーとグーを重ねるやつなら
やったけど…。
We did…fist bumps.
よし　ナルトだったな。
俺についてこい。
Okay. Naruto, right? Follow me.
ビーさんの修業場所に
連れてってやる。
I'll take you to
Bee's training spot.
やった！
（ヤマト）なら僕も。
All right!
Then I'll join you.
Captain Yamato?!
ヤマト隊長！
I'm a Wood-Style user
and if something happens,
木遁使いの僕は
一応　ナルトの世話役なんでね。
I'm supposed to look after him.
ほう　アンタが木遁の。
Oh? You're the Wood Style user.
いいだろう。
Fine then.
水　置いときますよ。
Here's some water.
あぁ…　助かる。
Oh, thanks.
まだ　ダメですか？
Still not feeling good?
いや　回復方向に
向かっているんだが→
Well, I feel like I'm recovering.
なんとなく　まだ　洋上を
漂っているような気がするのは→
But I can't shake the feeling
that I'm still at sea.
気のせいだろうかな？
Could it just be my imagination?
Yes. It's just your imagination.
気のせいですよ。
ここなのか？
Is this the place?
（モトイ）あぁ　ここは
真実の滝と呼ばれてる場所だ。
Yeah. This spot is known
as the Waterfall of Truth.
真実の滝…。
The Waterfall of Truth?
ここで　尾獣のコントロールを？
He learned to control
the Tailed Beast here?
いや　その前段階だ。
えっ？
No, it's the first step.
ここに座って　目を閉じろ　ナルト。
Sit here and close your eyes, Naruto.
そうすれば　お前の真実が見える。
You will see your true self.
俺の真実？
My true self?
そうだ。
Yes.
♪～
どうして…。
Why?
どうして　一楽で
サインを書かなかった？
Why didn't you give them
your autograph at Ichiraku?
なんだ？
What?
Those guys suddenly got nice
アイツら…
急に　手のひら返したように→
and tried to get friendly
with you, huh?
お前に
なれなれしくしてきたもんな。
うっとうしいヤツらだったもんな。
They were disgusting, weren't they?
This guy looks just like me!
《コイツ…　俺そっくりじゃねえか》
Everyone in the village used
to treat us like lepers.
里のヤツら…　今まで　さんざん
俺たちのことを→
のけものにしてきたくせによ。
((あっ　そうだ　サインくれ　サイン。
Oh hey! Give me
your autograph, Naruto!
うちの子に
書いてやってくんねえかな？
And address it to my kid.
He's a big fan of yours.
お前のファンでよ。
サイン？
Autograph?
The hero of the Hidden Leaf…
木ノ葉の英雄　奇跡を起こす少年
うずまきナルト。
The youth who created
a miracle, Naruto Uzumaki.
うちのほうにも　１枚　頼む！
Can I have one too?
What is it? You refuse?
どうした？　ダメか？
Oh no, but I'm not used
to that sort of thing.
いや…　俺ってば
そういうのに慣れてねえからよ。
I don't even have a signature.
(サインなんて持ってねえし))
誰だ？　お前は。
Who are you?
Can't you tell? I'm you.
見りゃ　わかんだろ。
俺は　お前だ。
はぁ！？　俺ってば
影分身　やった覚えはねえぞ。
I don't remember doing
Shadow Clones.
I'm the real you.
俺はお前自身…
お前の心の底にある　お前自身だ。
The real you that exists
deep inside your heart.
何　言ってんだ！？　テメエ！
What are you saying?!
I don't know you.
Stop making stuff up!
俺は　オメエなんか知らねえよ！
勝手なこと　言ってんじゃねえ！！
ナルト…　おい！
静かに。
Naruto, hey…
Quiet!
ここは
真実の滝とか言ってたな。
This place is called
the Waterfall of Truth, right?
ここまで　俺が
表に出てこられるとは…。
I never figured I'd be able
to come out like this.
What a great place.
いい場所だ！
つまり　俺はお前の真実だ。
Anyway, I'm your true self.
俺が　本当のお前だ。
The real you.
本当の…　俺？
The real me?
あぁ　俺はお前の大切な憎しみ…。
Yeah. I'm the precious hatred
inside you.
闇の部分だ。
The dark part of you!
The only difference is…
ただ　ひとつ　違うのは→
九尾のヤツに　やたらと
気に入られてるってことくらいか。
the Nine Tails has taken
a real liking to me.
お前…。
You…
The Nine Tails' will is
a mass of hatred
((九尾の意思ってのは
憎しみの塊で→
that binds itself tightly to chakra.
強い力で
チャクラと結びついてくるんじゃ。
No matter how hard you
try to shield yourself,
どんだけ　自分を強く保っても→
it will find some hatred that
you have buried deep inside
心のどこかにある憎しみと
結びつこうとして→
and try to take you over.
(心を乗っ取ってくる))
Until now, the Nine Tails
and this guy…
《今まで　コイツと九尾が…》
そういうことだ。
You got that right.
俺は　お前自身だ。
I'm the real one.
You can't kick me out, you fake!
追い出せはしねえぜ　ニセモノ。
そういうことか。
Is that how it is?
You're the fake one!
ニセモノは　テメエのほうだろ！
（キントキ）グルルル…。
Come on anytime.
いつでも　カモン！
グアーッ！
この島では　俺様がトップ。
すべてを倒す　俺様　突風。
On this island, I'm top dog.
Taking y'all down
Like a whirlwind clearing the fog.
まだまだ甘いぜ　キントキちゃんよ。
You still have a ways
to go, Kintoki.
（八尾）おい　ビー！　遊んでんなら→
Hey Bee…
If you had time to play around,
九尾のガキを見てやっても
よかったんじゃねぇか？
why couldn't you have taken
a look at the Nine Tails' kid?
同じ人柱力同士
もっと　協力してやってもよ。
You're both Jinchuriki,
why not give him a break?
俺も　九尾は好かねえが
あのガキは見込みがあるぜ。
I don't like Nine Tails myself,
but that kid has promise.
俺も　昔は　むちゃくちゃだったが
お前に会って　こうなった。
I was a confused mess back then,
but I met you and
look at me now.
なんとなく　昔のお前にも…。
He sort of reminds me of you.
ラップ風に　シャーラップ！
My style is rap
And I say shut yer trap!
I ain't acknowledgin' no rap-mockin'
"Ya know" fool
ラップをバカにする
てばヨーは認めねえ。
それに　アイツは…。
Besides, he…
クソ！
Damn it!
《まったく同じ力だ。
やり合っても　キリがねえ》
Our strength is identical.
There's no end to fighting him.
お前は　俺を倒せねえ。　絶対にな。
You can't beat me. Never.
Then I'll put my bet on numbers!
なら　数で勝負だ。
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
影分身の術。
What the hell?!
Is that how it is?!
なんだよ　そうなんのかよ！
Even the numbers of
Shadow Clones are the same!
影分身の数まで
同じじゃねえだろうな！？
よくわかってんじゃねぇかよ。
You're pretty smart,
figuring that out.
クッソー！　いっけ～！
Damn it!
Go!
いけっ！
何が…　どうなってるんです？
What is going on?
滝の前に座ると　集中し→
When you sit before
the waterfall and focus,
己の精神世界へ
入ることができる。
you are able enter
your subconscious.
そして　この滝は
己の本当の姿を映す鏡となる。
And the waterfall becomes
the mirror
that reflects your true self.
不思議な場所だ。
It is really a mystical place.
今　ナルトは
もう一人の自分と戦っている。
Right now, Naruto is batt
螺旋…。
丸！
カハッ！
ナルト　大丈夫か！？
何があった？
オレと…　同じヤツが出てきた。
ソイツは…。
なんだ？
闇の部分の俺だった。
俺と互角で
まったく同じ力で押してきやがる。
術も戦術パターンも
手の内が全部同じだ。
勝負がつかねえ…。
そんなことが…。
ソイツに勝たなけりゃ
尾獣の力は操れない。
え？
言ったはずだ。
この真実の滝は前段階だと。
♪～
（美空）
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。